Julian Beard

Software Engineer

 $(517)\ 626.4000 \cdot \underline{badjab326@gmail.com} \cdot \underline{Murrieta}, CA \cdot \underline{julianbeard.codes} \cdot \underline{in/Julian-A-Beard} \cdot \underline{github.com/badjab326}$

Software engineering graduate from General Assembly who's spent nearly ten years in various team based, customer facing positions, and gained an extensive repertoire of communication, team building and resource management skills.

SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python | Libraries and Frameworks - React, Node.js, Express.js, Django, EJS Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose | Other - RESTful Routing JSON, Docker, AWS S3

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

2022 - Present

What2Play

- Built from the ground up using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Ajax.
- Utilized an API to retrieve photos and information of random video games based on user preferences.
- Styled using flexbox, custom fonts and manually edited backgrounds and designed with mobile browsers in mind via responsive design.

Collarchive

- Manufactured multi-page create, read, update, delete (CRUD) app using Embedded JavaScript.
- Made RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all CRUD operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Defined schemas with Mongoose for MongoDB collections.

Avatar Yearbook

- Worked as Lead Backend Dev with a team of talented software engineers to create a digital yearbook for bootcamp graduates.
- Used React.js to serve the front-end with Javascript methods and functions.
- Served the back-end of the application using Express methods and functions utilizing MongoDB database management.
- Added Backend user authentication/authorization using Google Firebase.

Gym Planner

- Produced app designed to give users the ability to digitally plan, track and optimize their workouts.
- Constructed with Python, Django, Materialize CSS and PostgreSQL.
- Implemented full user authentication and authorization, as well as admin functionality.
- Modeled with MVT architecture, managed deployment pipeline with use of Heroku.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Idoona, Full-Stack Software Engineer | Bremen, Germany

Sep. 2022 - Present

- Assist with architecture for new software project, determining appropriate tech stack and MVP outline.
- Work with both front-end and backend technologies to develop a full-stack application based on client input.
- Use Mongo, Express, React, Node (MERN) and Sanity CMS to build and maintain our web-app.
- Apply Government supplied data to create a user-focused survey tool.

Alaska Airlines, Flight Attendant | Los Angeles, CA

Oct. 2017 - May 2022

- Enforced time management skills to work under tight time constraints to deliver optimal and safe service.
- Used strong communication and team management skills to work with highly diverse groups of people.
- Exerted patience and flexibility with adapting to constant changes in both the industry, and individual flights.
- Consistently learned and incorporated new skills and safety procedures into my workflow as needed.
- Handled secure information with care and confidence.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Immersive

April 2022 - July 2022

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, DevOps and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.